# Ljubomir JOSIFOVSKI





LjubomirJosifovski@gmail.com 🕒 +44 7910 850 111 👚 11 Pendennis Ct, Harpenden AL5 1SG, UK

# **Summary**

Quantitative researcher, analyst, developer, portfolio manager with extensive experience building and trading systematic equity/FX models at hedge funds, proprietary trading desk, and as an independent PM. Advanced skills in maths, statistics, machine learning, regression and classification, neural networks, hidden Markov models, and programming. Track record in modelling, forecasting, portfolio optimization, risk management, machine learning. Self-sufficient systems and network administrator.

## **Skills**

Programming: C/C++, MATLAB, Python, SQL, C#, R, Java, bash, awk, make Platforms: Linux (Ubuntu, CentOS), MacOS, Windows, Cloud computing

Tools: Vim, Git, Gemini-cli, Aider, Slurm, VSCode, Cline, CLion, Jupyter, Spyder, Bloomberg

# **Experience**

## F9 Research, Director (2016–Present)

Managed a market-neutral book (~\$350M gross, ~\$35M daily trading) in EU and US markets. Leading quant research and development for short-horizon strategies using Python, C++, cluster and cloud resources. Rekindled ML/AI interests using llama.cpp and open weights LLMs, Gemini and Aider coding agents, DNNs for tabular data forecasting (c.f. Hugging Face TabArena).

# Marshall Wace, Senior Quantitative Researcher (2010–2016)

Developed and scaled market-neutral portfolios from \$100M to \$10B+ over a period of 6 years. Pioneered unified R&D framework for data ingestion, signal extraction, modelling, portfolio optimization, simulation. Mentored junior researchers, implemented reproducible research workflows.

# **Credit Suisse, Quantitative Analyst (2007–2009)**

Independently traded equity market-neutral portfolios systematically, achieving 18% lifetime returns with Sharpe 3.1. Built and operated a complete trading platform for multi-market European equities.

# G-Research (DPFMG), Quantitative Analyst (2004–2007)

Designed and implemented systematic trading models for global equities and FX, contributing to fund profitability. Modelling, forecasting, risk management and multi-period optimization for mid- and high- frequency trading strategies.

# Canon Research Europe, Researcher (2001-2004)

Embedded Automatic Speech Recognition, indexing, and retrieval of spoken documents with speech.

## **Education**

Ph.D. Computer Science – University of Sheffield, UK (2000)

Thesis: Robust Speech Recognition with Missing and Unreliable Data

M.Phil. Electrical Engineering – University Sv. Kiril i Metodij, Skopje, MK (1997)

Thesis: System for text-to-speech conversion for Macedonian language

**B.S.** Electrical Engineering – University Sv. Kiril i Metodij, Skopje, MK (1993)

# Additional

UK and Macedonian nationality, multilingual (English, Macedonian-native, Croatian, Serbian) Married, two grown up children, UK and MK driving licenses

Interests include science, technology, epistemology, culture, solar punk, non-fiction, systems theories, political economy, quantitative finance, history, mentoring, e/acc.

# Ljubomir JOSIFOVSKI







🔯 LjubomirJosifovski@gmail.com 🔇 +44 7910 850 111 💣 11 Pendennis Court, Harpenden AL5 1SG, UK

## **Summary**

Quantitative researcher, analyst, developer, and portfolio manager with extensive experience building and trading systematic equity, FX models at hedge funds, proprietary trading desk, and as an independent portfolio manager. Advanced skills in mathematics, statistics, machine learning, AI and programming. Proven track record in modelling, forecasting, portfolio optimization, risk management. Systems and network administrator.

#### **Skills**

- Programming: C/C++, MATLAB, Python, SQL, C#, R, Java, bash, awk, make
- Platforms: Linux (Ubuntu, CentOS), MacOS, Windows
- Tools: Vim, Git, Gemini-cli, Aider, Slurm, VSCode, Cline, CLion, Jupyter, Spyder, Bloomberg

#### **Experience**

## F9 Research, Director (2016–Present)

- Managed a market-neutral book (~\$350M gross, ~\$35M daily trading) in EU and US markets.
- Led quantitative research and development for short-horizon strategies using C++, Python.
- ML/AI llama.cpp open weights LLMs, Gemini/Aider coding agents, tabular data forecasting DNNs

# Marshall Wace, Senior Quantitative Researcher (2010–2016)

- Developed and scaled market-neutral portfolios from \$100M to \$10B+ over a period of 6 years.
- Pioneered and wrote unified R&D frameworks for data ingestion, signal extraction, modelling, forecasting, portfolio optimization, simulation, execution, post-trade analysis.
- Mentored junior researchers, implemented reproducible research workflows.

# Credit Suisse, Quantitative Analyst (2007–2009)

- Independently traded equity market-neutral portfolios systematically, 18% lifetime returns Sharpe 3.1.
- Built and operated a complete trading platform for multi-market European equities.

## G-Research (DPFMG), Quantitative Analyst (2004–2007)

- Designed and implemented systematic trading models for global equities and FX for fund profitability.
- Specialized in modelling, forecasting, risk management, and multi-period optimization for mid- and high- frequency trading strategies.

## Canon Research Europe, Researcher (2001–2004)

• Embedded automatic speech recognition, indexing, and retrieval of spoken documents.

## Education

- Ph.D., Computer Science University of Sheffield, UK (2000) Thesis: Robust Speech Recognition with Missing and Unreliable Data
- M.Phil., Electrical Engineering University Sv. Kiril i Metodij, Skopje, MK (1997) Thesis: System for Text-to-Speech Conversion for the Macedonian Language
- B.S., Electrical Engineering University Sv. Kiril i Metodij, Skopje, MK (1993)

#### Additional

- Dual citizenship UK and Macedonian, multilingual: English, Macedonian (native), Croatian, Serbian
- Married, two grown up children, driving licenses UK MK, Interests include science, technology, epistemology, culture, solar punk, systems theories, political economy, history, mentoring, e/acc.